

TRAN THANH THAO

Senior Procurement - Partnership and Operations

Thaott200694@gmail.com



0903.603.782



thaotran94

I have gained over 6 years of experience in a retail company in terms of value-added Services and Accessories. This has helped me gain more diverse skills and a professional mindset in both Business Development and Operations. I am open-minded, adaptable, and responsible. One of my strong strengths is logical thinking and problem-solving skills. I am looking forward to having the opportunity to contribute my efforts to your company's development.

Work Experience -

FAMILY WAREHOUSE – Online Sale Start-Up – April 2023 – Present



I am a key person responsible for developing and executing online sales of products such as Tshirts and Thai footwear through various social media platforms (e.g., Facebook, Shopee, Instagram).

Business Development & Operation:

- Conduct market research to identify and understand trends and customer behavior to maximize growth.
- Manage sell-in & sell-out plans and pricing strategies, ensuring pricing remains competitive with other stores.
- Develop customer loyalty programs to increase repeat purchases through special offers and create promotions for special days and peak seasons.
- Create and manage content for product descriptions, promotional materials and social media posts to increase engagement and conversion rates.

Strategic Partnership Management.

- Work closely with suppliers and vendors to optimize pricing, delivery schedules and quality of products.
- Cultivate and maintain strong customer relationships: ensuring timely delivery and quality of products before delivery to customers.

FPT RETAIL - Senior Procurement - Operation and Partnership Management - Sep 2021 - Mar 2023



I was responsible for developing and implementing policies and pricing strategies for the products the team worked on, including over 10 accessory brands (e.g., JBL, Sony, Marshall, Bose, Asus, Logitech, Hyper, Anker, Belkin).

Business Development & Operation:

- Worked closely with the team to analyze market trends and customer behavior to map out plans for yearly strategies, steadily increasing revenue and profit by 20% each year, with the target of reaching an average annual revenue of 600 billion VNĐ.
- Created promotional campaigns and sales contests for the sales team and regions to achieve an average revenue of 50 billion VNĐ and profit of 25 billion VNĐ per month (e.g., the "iPhone 14" campaign increased revenue by over 15% and profit by over 30% compared to the same period last year).
- Came up with solutions to control P&L (e.g., negotiate with suppliers for a better price).
- Worked on pricing strategies, and made sure they were competitive with competitors in the market and company profitability goals.
- Controlled inventory turnover safety and managed sell-in and sell-out plans, ensuring that stock was always available to meet customer demand during special days and peak seasons.
- Oversaw the implementation of business activities related to process improvements, promotions, and product operations, ensuring smooth and continuous execution.
- Made decisions related to business based on working closely with the stakeholders and goals as a whole.

Strategic Partnership Management.

- Managed and maintained relationships with over 20 partners, ensuring smooth communication and collaboration.
- Analysed and identified opportunities for growth and expansion within partnerships.
- Established and managed strategic partnerships, coordinating promotions with key partners.
- Negotiated contracts, and evaluated financial viability for new initiatives.

Leadership and Team Management

- Managed a team of 10 members, ensuring efficient collaboration and achieving team objectives.
- Performance tracking: Monitor KPIs and division OKR to deliver overall business objectives, allocate tasks, and ensure that deadlines are met.
- Conducted regular performance reviews and provided constructive feedback to enhance individual and team performance.
- Coached and mentored team members to maximize their strength.

FPT RETAIL – Procurement – Operation and Partnership Management Executive - July 2021 – Sep 2021



I was in charge of developing the category of accessories related to Mobile phones and Laptops (e.g., Power banks, Speakers, Headphones, Earphones, Memory cards).

Business Development & Collaboration:

- Revenue and Profit growth: Reached a total of 20 billion VNĐ per month, achieved over 90% of the target. This contributed over 35% of total revenue from accessories.
- Identified solutions, and action plans and made sell-in and sell-out plans to drive target.
- Executed the purchase order regularly.
- Compared pricing and promotions with competitors to adjust quickly and ensure the best price for customers.
- Worked on the contract terms & conditions (e.g., price, payment, delivery, promotions) for special days and peak seasons.
- Optimized and distributed goods across the stores and ensure inventory turnover safety.

Partnership Management & Operation:

- Cultivated and maintained strong relationships with partners.
- Researched and analyzed market trends, customer needs and competitor products to expand the category worked on.
- Collaborated with other departments, including legal, e-commerce, customer service, and marketing to launch campaigns (e.g., new iPhone, Samsung, back to school), ensuring the system runs smoothly and continuously.
- Other tasks as assigned by the Line Manager: made reports daily/weekly, track P&L

FPT RETAIL – Product Manager of Installment – 2016 – 2021



A key person in charge of collaborating with the banks and finance companies to offer payment solutions to customers, helping them make purchasing decisions more easily.

- Collaborated with over 10 banks (e.g., HSBC, Citibank, Techcombank) and more than 3 finance companies (e.g., Home Credit, FE Credit, HD SASION, Mirae Asset) to implement policies and define schemes that serve customers in the peak seasons.
- Worked closely with stakeholders to operate and maintain processes, and found solutions to make the process easier and more convenient.
- Developed the process for executing installment contracts created by sellers on the mobile app, reducing processing time by 50% and leading to enhanced customer satisfaction.
- Proposed action plans and tracked sales performance daily to achieve business objectives.
- Supported sales teams in selling consistently 24/7 and other tasks as assigned by the Line Manager: made reports daily/weekly, tracked P&L.
- **Achievement:** "The Individual Gold Award" in the third quarter of 2019, "Best Manager" in 2019, and "Top 100 Best Employees" in 2019.

Education

HCM COLLEGE OF ECONOMICS 2013 – 2016

- Bachelor of International Business
- Certificate Of Fundamental Business Analysis in BAC

Skills

- Business Planning
- Project/Product Management
- Operation Management
- Business Analyst IT and SQL Basic Knowledge
- Problem Solving
- Negotiation
- Communication
- Leadership & Team Management